# **Cheney Ni**

Philadelphia PA Area

cheneyni.451@gmail.com in cheneyni | Cheneyni-451

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a software engineer with a few years of web devlopment experience in **TypeScript** and the **React** framework. I am familiar with REST APIs, AWS tools, such as DynamoDB and Lambda, and have worked with the microservice architecture.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : TypeScript, JavaScript, C++, Python, SQL, CSS

**Frameworks** : React

**Databases** : DynamoDB

Software : Git, GitHub, Linux

### EXPERIENCE

# **Software Development Engineer I**

Amazon Web Services Inc.

Feb 2023 - April 2023

Remote - New York, NY

- Improved user experience of internship project after receiving feedback after deployment
- Enhanced development workflow by integrating code review status notifications into a Slack channel to increase visibility of new code reviews
- Removed expired data in **DynamoDB** table through scripting, resulting in a table size reduction of over 90%, thus lowering operational costs
- Collaborated with team members to expedite tasks to be ready for upcoming production deployment

#### **Software Development Engineer Intern**

Amazon Web Services Inc.

May 2022 - August 2022 New York, NY

- Designed an implementation of a new digest email feature and reviewed it with entire team for feedback
- Implemented a reworked design of an entire webpage using TypeScript and React to enhance the customizability of the user experience
- Worked with an assortment of **AWS** tools, such as **Pinpoint** to send email and SMS notifications to customers, and **DynamoDB** to store user data

# **Software Development Intern**

Red Rover

June 2021 - August 2021 Exton, PA

- Collaborated with senior developers and another intern to fix bugs in web application using TypeScript React
- Communicated with the Sales team through daily Agile meetings to target and fix high priority bugs
- Wrote regression tests for the UI using Cypress testing framework

#### EDUCATION

Online Sudoku Solver Personal Project

- Implemented a browser extension in JavaScript to automatically solve online sudoku puzzles
- Designed with extensibility to allow adding parsers in the future for other sudoku websites
- · Coded sudoku solver using a backtracking algorithm

Thread Library School Project

- Developed a user-level thread library in C++ for the Linux OS in a team of 3 to learn about concurrency
- Implemented FIFO CPU scheduling to manage and switch between threads, and mutexes and conditional variables to allow thread synchronization
- Designed multithreaded programs to test the robustness of our implementation of the thread library

Network File Server School Project

- Developed a low-level network file server in a team with read-write support and communicating through TCP
- Designed with multithreading to allow concurrent operations from an abritrary number of clients
- Engineered file server to be consistent regardless of erratic system crashes